DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR • DATA MODELING • ORACLE • POSTGRES



iosephgohlke2020@gmail.com



in www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-gohlke-2020a



407.619.3135

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Database Administrator based in Orlando, Florida with over 30 years experience supporting large development projects. Involved in all phases of software development life cycle. Mentor and lead for DBA team. Manage long-term development projects and customer reported problems. Conduct on-site training for application sub-systems. Provide persistent data management for core application data. Lead effort to secure production Oracle and Postgres databases using guidance provided by the DOD Security Technical Implementation Guide (STIG). Help to create infrastructure to support security updates and IAVA patching for fielded systems.

CLEARANCE

Active TS/SCI

SKILLS

Database Administrator

Data Modeling

PL/SQL • SQL • Shell

Java • JDBC

Data Warehouse

Agile

Security • IAVA • STIG

Technical Instructor

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR (DBA TEAM LEAD/SECURITY/TRAINER)

Dignitas Technologies, December 2014 - Present

DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR/SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (DBA TEAM LEAD/SECURITY/TRAINER)

SAIC/LEIDOS, October 2000 – December 2014 SAIC, October 1998 – August 1999

CONSULTANT/PRESIDENT (SYSTEM INTEGRATOR/TRAINER)

Teleri Systems Inc, September 1999 - October 2000

CONSULTANT (DBA/SOFTWARE DEVELOPER)

Fracdata Inc, April 1998 - November 1998

SOFTWARE LEAD

ACE*COMM Corp, February 1997 - April 1998

ACCOUNT MANAGER (GOLD SUPPORT)

Oracle Corp, January 1996 - February 1997

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (JAVA, C, C++)

Fidelity Investments, May 1994 - January 1996

SOFTWARE LEAD/DEVELOPER

Cincinnati Bell Information Systems (CBIS), July 1986 -May 1994

ADJUNCT INSTRUCTOR (C PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE)

Valencia College, April 1991 - May 1994

DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR • DATA MODELING • ORACLE • POSTGRES



josephgohlke2020@gmail.com



in www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-gohlke-2020a



407.619.3135

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Computer Science, **1986** *University of Central Florida*

Oracle Certified DBA Oracle v8, 2002

TOOLS

GIT • JIRA • Bitbucket

Jenkins • Artifactory

Clearcase • Clearquest

SQLDeveloper

Navicat • Datagrip

Microsoft Office Suite

MILITARY SERVICE

US Army

Enlisted Nov 1977 - Nov 1983

OH-58 Helicopter crew chief. Honorably discharged.

HOBBIES

SCUBA Diver - Certifications

Open Water
Advanced Open Water
Enriched Air
Full Face Mask

Wood Working Metal Working

Boating

EXPERIENCE DETAILS

DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR (DBA TEAM LEAD/SECURITY/TRAINER)

Dignitas Technologies, December 2014 - Present

Database Administration for large DOD Simulation and Training application for both development and fielded systems. Supported development of several large software projects that included data modeling, data conversion, systems integration, customer acceptance and fielding. Database design and implementation included performance tuning and securing the database by implementing STIG recommendations. Roll-out included security review by DOD, security issue resolution and management of the process through issuance of an Authority to Operate (ATO).

- Team Lead for DBA team schedule management, task assignment, task prioritization
- Lead for persistent core data for simulation. Managed regular updates, patching and user interface for data subsystem.
- Lead for After Action Reporting subsystem. Developed reports, created patches and interfaced with customer to gather requirements and resolve issues.
- Scrum Lead of 8-person Scrum team that converted entire program from Oracle 12 to Postgres 11. Project spanned 8 months and was completed on-time and under budget.

DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR • DATA MODELING • ORACLE • POSTGRES



l

in www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-gohlke-2020a



407.619.3135

EXPERIENCE DETAILS

DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR/SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (DBA TEAM LEAD/SECURITY/TRAINER)

SAIC/LEIDOS, October 2000 – December 2014 SAIC, October 1998 – August 1999

Database Administration and Software Developer for large DOD Simulation and Training application for both development and fielded systems. Developed and supported several large software projects. Development included all phases of software development lifecycle. Performed extensive performance tuning in the database and database applications for data warehouse reporting application. Participated in hardware evaluation and made recommendations for system specification.

- Software Team Lead Lead the effort to design, develop and test database interface for simulation user interface.
- Created an application to ingest a Federate Object Model (FOM) and produce scripts for a full Oracle-compliant data model.
- Software Team Member Provided database API packages in C/C++ and Java.

CONSULTANT/PRESIDENT (SYSTEM INTEGRATOR/TRAINER)

Teleri Systems Inc, September 1999 - October 2000

Consulting work for previous employer (ACE*COMM) at a remote location. Worked with system integrators and support personnel to convert to ACE*COMM's telephony management system.

CONSULTANT (DBA/SOFTWARE DEVELOPER)

Fracdata Inc, April 1998 - November 1998

Software development and database administration for Federal Express application. Designed software and database to FedEx requirements for managing packages through customs in 15 countries in South America and the Caribbean.

SOFTWARE LEAD

ACE*COMM Corp, February 1997 – April 1998

Lead a team of 8-15 software developers in remote Central Florida office. Helped open the office, recruited and hired staff. Managed daily software development operations.

DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR • DATA MODELING • ORACLE • POSTGRES



in www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-gohlke-2020a



407.619.3135

EXPERIENCE DETAILS

ACCOUNT MANAGER (GOLD SUPPORT)

Oracle Corp, January 1996 - February 1997

Account Manager for several Oracle customers at the premium (1M+/year) support level. Acted as Sales Engineer during presales activities and managed customer support interface for Oracle across all business lines. Was first level escalation for all customer support issues.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (JAVA, C, C++)

Fidelity Investments, May 1994 - January 1996

Software developer for large integration project to create a unified set of reports, user interfaces and invoices across 70+ independent entities inside Fidelity Investments.

SOFTWARE LEAD/DEVELOPER

Cincinnati Bell Information Systems (CBIS), July 1986 -May 1994

Software Developer and Team Lead for Telephony Billing application in use by large commercial facilities, colleges and military bases. Worked with new customers to understand business needs. Helped design and develop custom-created software to manage their telephony billing activities. Provided telephone and on-site support for newly converted customers.

ADJUNCT INSTRUCTOR (C PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE)

Valencia College, April 1991 - May 1994

Created curriculum, presented material, managed student lab activities, prepared and graded tests.